<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Privacy | SquareLemon]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.squarelemon.com/blog/categories/privacy/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.squarelemon.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-04T12:01:12-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.squarelemon.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Lee Brotherson]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[contact@squarelemon.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[No we don't]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.squarelemon.com/blog/2015/01/02/no-we-dont/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-02T10:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.squarelemon.com/blog/2015/01/02/no-we-dont</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just got a festive present from my ISP, <a href="http://www.rogers.com">Rogers</a>.<br /><br /></p>

<p>Following my <a href="http://blog.squarelemon.com/blog/2014/10/29/corporation-in-the-middle/">recent <a href="http://blog.squarelemon.com/blog/2014/12/24/bsides-toronto-video-and-slides/">talks</a> regarding ISP packet injection/interception and data collection I wrote to the privacy officer at Rogers and asked, under PIPEDA, that I be supplied all information regarding my account, including any information that they have gathered such as URLs of sites visited, etc.<br /></p>

<br />


<p>I got a fairly standard response which said that they did not collect any such data, to which I replied:<!-- More --></p>

<br />


<p><blockquote><p>Hi,</p></p><p><p>I recently sent a letter to you asking for details of data that Rogers hold on me as required by PIPEDA.  As expected you, or someone in your department, kindly replied.  Thank you!</p></p><p><p>Most of it made sense however I did note that there was one area in particular that is inaccurate/untrue, specifically your statement &ldquo;We do not collect the IP addresses or the domain names of the sites that you have visited or the time, dates and port numbers&rdquo;.  I understand it is entirely possible that this was not deliberate and it&rsquo;s more likely that you are unaware of some of the data that Rogers holds, nonetheless I thought that I should mention this so that this mistake is not replicated in the future placing you in breach of PIPEDA.</p></p><p><p>To provide you some insight, when you insert consumer messaging into webpages, such as the &ldquo;you have exceeded 75% of your bandwidth allowance&hellip;&rdquo; message, you use a system called the Bulletin System manufactured by Perftech to do so.  Putting aside the legality of this tool (I believe this breaks the Telecommunications Act) for a moment, you should note that this tool tracks user web browsing behavior (other than encrypted sessions) and keeps a history of the past 30 days tied to user account, irrespective of if that user is receiving any messaging at the time or not.</p></p><p><p>If it helps you to track down this system, one of it&rsquo;s nodes (REDACTED) is currently live on the IP REDACTED within your network.</p></p><p><p>If you would like further information on this I have a sizeable amount of documentation and evidence to support this.</p></p><p><p>Please feel free to come back to me if you have any questions or queries.</p></p><p><p>Thanks</p></p><p><p>Lee</p></blockquote></p>

<br /><br />


<p>Their response?<br /><br /></p>

<p><img src="http://blog.squarelemon.com/images/corp_in_the_middle/rogers_letter_update.jpeg"></p>

<br /><br />


<p>I don&rsquo;t feel that this is going to progress anytime soon.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
